https://moondanceadventures.com/privacy-policy/

Trip Finder
Toggle navigation
800.832.5229 Contact Enroll ×Why MoondanceAbout UsMeet Our FounderFAQsGiving BackWork With MoondanceLeader PortalParent PortalTrip Comparison ChartExplore All TripsTrips by Grade6th Grade7th Grade8th Grade9th Grade10th Grade11th Grade12th GradeMy FavoritesTrips by DivisionDiscoveryClassicLeadershipServiceStills + MotionTrip UpdatesGear StoreUnplugged Blog Enroll Now
Moondance Adventures Privacy PolicyAll information provided to Moondance Adventures will remain private. We will never sell or provide this information to any other companies.SEPTEMBER 30, 2018Our RelationshipWe’re in the kid business and our goal is to create trips of a lifetime. Here at Moondance, we strive to deliver amazing adventures, the opportunity to travel the world, and the chance to further develop one’s love for the outdoors. In doing so, we prepare well in advance for the success of our programs and an integral component of the preparation of our programs involves the collection and organization of data on Moondance applicants and their families. Obviously, the more we know about our students, the better we can customize and improve their experience. As we plan our programs, we will ask you for personal information (some mandatory, some optional); in turn, we will protect this information and ensure that it remains confidential. We also promise never to sell your information to anyone.What We Ask For & WhyYou can register for a Moondance program by enrolling online or by contacting our admissions team in the Moondance office. At that time, we will ask you to provide some basic information (such as your name, your child’s name/gender, their school, your phone number, medical information, credit card number and expiration date) so that we can identify you, follow up with you and process your application and/or enrollment. This information is then transferred to your Moondance trip leaders and guides, who will in turn make the appropriate adjustments and/or contact the various suppliers and facilities. In some instances, we may need additional information. Below is a description of some of the extra information we may require:Physical and Health DetailsWe need to obtain information about your child’s general health and health conditions as well as data like age, gender, and height so that we can provide him/her with the appropriate equipment and care. Medical forms with a physician’s signature and approval are required prior to your child’s summer program with forms to be submitted to the Moondance office.Flight and Passport InformationWe require your child’s flight information in order to orchestrate and organize airport retrieval and/or drop-off services with the Moondance leaders. For international trips, we request passport information because it is required by our administrative office and often local service providers.Dietary RequirementsWe understand that many people prefer or are required to follow certain diets. While many of our programs take place in a backcountry setting, we try to accommodate these choices and needs whenever possible. We recommend discussing any dietary requirements prior to enrolling so we can ensure your requirements can be met. To accomplish dietary accommodation, your dietary preferences and needs must be communicated with our office and recorded during our forms process.Personal PreferencesMoondance Adventures constantly strives to provide you and your family with the highest level of personal service. Our admissions team will record any special requests or preferences that are specified at the time of your application and/or enrollment. This information is passed on to your student’s leaders and enables the organization to meet and exceed all of your expectations. Also, our leaders may pass on information about special requests or preferences expressed by students while on a trip. We maintain a record of this information to ensure that on subsequent programs, these personal preferences continue to be accommodated. We also keep a record of past trips your child has taken with us, which allows us to understand the type of activities or trips your child prefers, leadership characteristics, and to determine what information (i.e. about new or revised programs) your family might find interesting.Our Email NewsletterMoondance Adventures e-mail newsletter provides regular updates and articles about Moondance trips, students, leaders, and other relevant information. To sign up for this service, we ask that you provide us with your name and your e-mail address. You may unsubscribe at any time by using the link provided on every newsletter.Information UseBrochuresWe use your address information and personal preference details to mail you select Moondance brochures and catalogs. If at any point you wish to have your name removed from our mailing list, please contact us at info@moondanceadventures.com or by phone at 1.800.832.5229.ResearchFrom time to time, Moondance will retain the assistance of external service organizations to help us understand our students, travellers, and any trends in our industry. We may disclose some of your personal information to those companies solely for the purpose of conducting research and analysis on behalf of Moondance Adventures. We use contractual and other means to protect your information while our agents are processing it. We are always interested in how our students and families first heard about Moondance, and we may ask you for information about how you discovered us and what types of media you watch and read. We gather this information to enable us to understand which marketing and advertising tools are most effective for our business.Website analyticsWe seek to improve our website and the online services we offer. As part of these efforts, we collect and analyze certain information about visitors to our website. This data includes (but is not limited to) domain and/or web browser information, your IP address along with the URL you came from and which URLS you visit our site at www.moondanceadventures.com, as well as time spent on the page. However, we do not link any information that would make your IP address personally identifiable.CookiesWe do use cookies (small data files for data tracking and recording keeping) to collect information. You are able to set your we browser to refuse the use of cookies if you wish and this may make certain aspects of our website un-usable like our application system and parent portal.Our Promise to YouAt Moondance, we understand the importance of privacy. We treat our students as part of our family and carefully protect all the information they have entrusted to us. The information we request from you will enable us to provide you with the highest levels of personal service on every Moondance trip. We will not disclose any personal information to any external company or person, except as described above, without a family/parent’s informed consent unless we are required by law to do so. With the growth of electronic media, we recognize that it is necessary to take further steps to protect the privacy of the individual. We simply do not share data or breach your confidentiality with information you have disclosed.Your Right to Review Your InformationAll Moondance parents, families, and children are entitled to examine the information we keep regarding them, subject to any restrictions required by law, and may request rectification of inaccurate or incomplete information.ComplaintsIf you feel that Moondance has not complied with this Privacy Policy or if you are otherwise concerned with the Moondance Adventures personal information practices, then you may file a complaint by sending a letter to Moondance Adventures, Inc., 209 10th Avenue South, Suite 322 Nashville, Tenn. 37203, or send an email to info@moondanceadventures.com. Complaints or requests for information shall be the object of an investigation or response within 30 business days. If the complaint is justified, Moondance will take the appropriate measures to address the complaint, including access to the requested information, by proceeding with rectification or, as the case may be, by amending its Policy and practices. Trip FinderTrip ComparisonJobsStoreParent PortalContactCovid-19 PoliciesSitemapPrivacy PolicyEmail Us800.832.5229 ×Get in TouchContact Us800.832.5229 615.610.5900 9am-5pm M-F CST info@moondanceadventures.comMAILING ADDRESS PO Box 23350 Nashville, TN 37202PHYSICAL ADDRESS 209 Tenth Avenue South Suite 322 Nashville, TN 37203Get Our Catalog Virtual By MailFollow Us
Parent Portal Login Leaders Login ×About Our DivisionsDiscoveryGrades 6th-7thFirst times stay with you forever, and our Discovery trips will give you an unforgettable introduction to outdoor adventure. For those with an appetite for the wild, or those who have never slept beneath the stars, these multi-sport adventures will introduce you to a lifetime of exploration. ClassicGrades 7th-9thFrom the golden coast, to the purple mountains majesty, expand your homeland on one of our Classic Trips. These expeditions are designed to show you vast beauty and adventure. Multi-sport trips take you climbing, rafting, backpacking, paddling and discovering the most stunning wildernesses in the land of the free.LeadershipGrades 9th-12thLeadership trips are crafted to hone your expedition skills in the most rugged, challenging and beautiful terrain we offer. One part wilderness immersion, one part leadership curriculum, these adventures are designed for those looking to increase their skills in the wild and in the world. Bring out your most confident and competent self on one of our Leadership trips.ServiceGrades 8th-12thSome of the wildest and most wondrous destinations can open your eyes to the greatness of giving back. Our Service trips are designed to take you off the beaten path with a purpose. Immerse yourself in a deeper version of adventure travel, by making a positive impact on the communities and environments you visit. ×About AvailabilityAvailable for 2021We are excited to offer this trip in 2021. Dates will be announced soon.AvailableThere are still spaces available on this trip! Get in touch with us if you are interested in this trip, as availability can change quickly.LimitedWe have limited availability on this trip. If you’re interested in a spot on this date and session, please call the office as soon as possible to learn more.WaitlistWhile this trip is currently full, we are accepting applications for a waitlist. Please complete our online application to ensure your spot on the waitlist. We’ll call you to discuss options once we receive it.We place limiting factors on students from the same school or hometown. We also strive for equally balanced co-ed groups. These factors may be relevant.
Enroll
